MUHAMMAD HAMZA

Undergraduate Student of Geo-Information & Earth Observation

PERSONAL INFO

Address:

Room 315, Jinnah Hostel, Shamsabad, Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Phone:

+92-3073269360

E-mail:

mhwahla360@gmail.com

Date & place of birth:

1996-01-11, Rahimyarkhan

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ mhwahla

SKILLS

- GIS | Remote Sensing
- **Image Processing**
- Data Science & Analytics
- Web Development
- Digital & Geomarketing
- SEO/Local Listing
- **Public Speaking**

SOFTWARES | LANGUAGES

Python	ArcGIS	
MapInfo	ArcHydro	
QGIS	ERDAS	
ENVI	Geomatica	
Global Mapper ESA Snap		
Google Earth App Engine		
GrADs/CDO	GeoODK	
MATLAB	C/C++	
JavaScript	WordPress	
Django	GeoServer	
SQL	PostGIS	
Photoshop	Illustrator	
AutoCAD	MS Office	

With practical command over **open-source** as well as commercial GIS & Satellite Image Processing tools, I am versed in spatial analysis, geodatabases & digital mapping. Also proficient in web development & have 4 years of freelance writing experience. I am a strong proponent of FOSS4G, Volunteer GIS & open geo-data such as **OpenStreetMap**. My academic experience has given me exposure towards developmental, urban & transportation & environmental planning issues. I believe GIS is a mean of bridging different fields of earth & social sciences. Also a keen Data Science, Machine **Learning, Deep Learning & Computer Vision** enthusiast. I have proven academic achievements & possess the right technical & soft skills required to propel the organization in achieving its goals & objectives.



2016 - Present

2012 - 2014

EDUCATION

• BS Geo-Informatics (6th Semester) Arid Agriculture University Rawalpindi | CGPA: 2.9/4.00

Courses: Object Oriented Programming | GIS | Remote Sensing | Digital Image Processing | Geo-Database Systems | Web GIS Development | CAD | Computer Graphics | Surveying | Soil Mechanics | Cartography | Photogrammetry | Geodesy | Earth & Weather Sciences | Navigation Systems | Physical & Human Geography | Environmental Engineering | Spatial Data Infrastructure & Decision Support Systems | GIS Programming

Higher Secondary School Certificate Pre Medical A Grade	
 Iqra Public School, Sadiqabad Secondary School Certificate Biology and Physics A Grade 	2010 – 2012
EXPERIENCE	
Fiverr GIS Analyst (level 1)	2017 – Present
Senior GIS freelancer GIS Development , Analysis and Dashboarding	
GIS Seekein	2016 - Present
Founder Video tutorials & online training on GIS, Remote Sensing	
MER Consultants	2018 – 2019
GIS Intern Data Preparation, Regional Mapping and GIS tasking	
SAGRS Society	2019 - Present

CERTIFICATES		
• Youth N	lational Award Winner (GIS Category)	NYAC, March 2018
• Web OD	OM (Open Drone Mapping)	Github, September 2018
 Comput 	ation and Python MIT OCW	August 2018
• GIS Surv	veyor	PITB, April 2018

PERSONAL PROJECTS

GPS device developed from scratch (fully functional)

Founder | Training on GIS, Remote Sensing

- **911 Call Prediction** in US using Exploratory Data Analysis
- Automated **Snow** Cover Area **Change Detection** in UIB using MODIS Timeseries
- 3D point cloud conversion into DEM

Punjab College Sadigabad

- Mapping 2017 Karachi Floods using Sentinel-1 SAR Data
- **Arc-GIS Tool Development**
- 7. ArcGIS based **Navigation** System for Hyderabad City
- 8. Groundwater Modelling in Islamabad using OBIA and MCDA
- **GWR Geographic Weighted Regression Analysis**
- 10. Geodatabase Development for a Hypothetical Smart City in ArcGIS
- 11. Assessment of Minerals using ASTER- SAR-Land Sat Composite Data
- 12. Mangrove Change Detection in Indus Delta Wetland (1988-2018) using Landsat